<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>venture-capital on Roy Roth Homepage</title>
    <link>http://roykroth.com/tags/venture-capital/</link>
    <description>Recent content in venture-capital on Roy Roth Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Roy Roth</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://roykroth.com/tags/venture-capital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flexibility Versus Agency - A Model of Stage Financing (Job Market Paper)</title>
      <link>http://roykroth.com/project/staging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://roykroth.com/project/staging/</guid>
      <description>I explore the optimal timing of financing for venture capital-backed companies. In doing so, I make a distinction between staged investment and staged financing, and focus on the latter. Raising a larger percentage of the total needed funds upfront presents operational efficiencies, lowering the cost of the project, but increases the scale of agency problems and sacrifices the option value of delay. The optimal financing path depends upon the relative magnitudes of efficiency gains from upfront financing and the value of waiting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk and Incentives in Venture Capital - A Portfolio Perspective</title>
      <link>http://roykroth.com/project/risk-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://roykroth.com/project/risk-incentives/</guid>
      <description>I explore conflicts of interest between venture capitalists (VCs) and entrepreneurs (Es). When the venture capital portfolio consists of only a single investment, the VC and E face exactly the same incentives concerning the risk profile and exit strategy. However, as the portfolio grows the picture changes dramatically, giving rise to important conflicts of interest. Specifically, when the portfolio experiences a large positive outcome the concavity of the VC&amp;rsquo;s payoff effectively induces risk aversion, with VC preferring safer strategies than E.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>